ALEX OSORO OGETO

FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

Gmail | GitHub |LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack developer with 1 year of experience building, testing, and deploying user-focused websites and applications. Open-source enthusiast with an affection for clean code, pair programming, and remote enthusiast. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies, and capable of sloping up rapidly and productively

SKILLS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools **Professional**: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Problem Solving, Time Management

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) August 2022-Present

Mentor junior web developers, and offer technical support through code reviews.

 Give counsel on the most proficient method to keep up with the inspiration and the program's longevity.

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

June 2022-Present.

<u>Bookstore-Website</u> — Provides an online platform to store books of any kind and helps keep track of all the book coverage progress as you read.

• Built with: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React & Redux. View the project on GitHub

<u>Awesome Books</u> —Permit clients to add wanted books to the rundown and furthermore erase books. It utilizes nearby capacity to save the information on the internet browser.

• Built with: HTML, CSS, Webpack, and JavaScript. View the project on GitHub

My Portfolio — A professional portfolio that is a collection of examples and evidence to showcase experience capability, and potential for employment opportunities and professional development.

• Built with: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. View the project on GitHub

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE June 2022–June 2023

Remote FullStack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

DEDAN KIMATHI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

May 2018-December 2021

Bachelor Of Science In Industrial Chemistry

- Skills attained were Analysis and problem-solving, Time management and organization, Written and oral communication, Teamwork, and Research & Presentation.
- Member of Dedan Kimathi University Chemistry Club.